I only have three main points in my presentation
Other than that
I don’t have anything else to say
Those main points can be elaborated on
Sometimes you need to explain further
so the audience can understand the content better
Elaboration means you provide more details
You could say “let me give you some more information”
or “let me elaborate on …”
as an introduction to further explain your points
And, use facts or statistics to support your statements
Say something like “based on our findings …,”
“according to a recent study …,”
or “the data shows …”
What if the audience misunderstands me
or gets confused?
Should I wait until the very end of the presentation
to answer their questions?
Whenever you feel a point needs to be clarified
use “what I mean is…” or “in other words…”
to rephrase and clarify your meaning
You could also say “to put it simply”
or "let me just say that another way."
The better the elaboration
the less confused the audience will be
Good idea
What if the audience has a different opinion
after my presentation?
How can I persuade them?
When you present an argument
you should state why the audience
should support your idea
Giving some examples might convince them
and help them understand the concept better
You could use phrases like
“for instance…,” “to illustrate…”
or “let’s take this example…”
You can also use analogies
to compare an abstract idea with a concrete one
An analogy is a comparison between two things
that have similar features
Here is a well-known example of an analogy
“Just like a sword is the weapon of a warrior
a pen is the weapon of a writer.”
That’s a really good analogy.
Make your analogy easy for the audience to relate to
It needs to be short and simple
Couldn’t agree with you more
We are learning something new and true every day
Like the analogy says:
The truth in every myth is the pearl in every oyster